Contact

6411 Fannin Street Houston, TX 77030 281-438-0902 (Home) darlinemurdock2188@comcast. net

www.linkedin.com/in/darlenemurdock-bsn-ba-rn-cnor-cssmtncc-a3117b30 (LinkedIn)

Top Skills

Healthcare ACLS Nursing

Certifications

Certified Security Supervision & Management (CSSM)

Trauma Nurse Curriculum Course (TNCC)

Darlene Murdock, BSN, BA, RN, CNOR, CSSM, TNCC

Empowered, Engaged, Effective Perioperative Nurse Leader Missouri City, Texas

Summary

Darlene B. Murdock, BSN, BA, RN, CNOR is a certified perioperative nurse with over 25 years of exprience specializing in trauma. She graduated from the University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston with a Bachelor of Science in Nursing. Darlene has also earned a Bachelor's of Arts in Business Administration from the University of North Carolina at Charlotte. Ms. Murdock is employed as a clinical staff RN IV at Memorial Hermann in the Texas Medical Center. She is presently serving as a member of AORN's Board of Directors. As an expert clinician, Darlene serves as an effective change agent functioning in the roles of leader, advocator, educator, collaborator, innovator, and mentor in efforts to continuously elevate the nursing profession and optimal patient care. As a magnet council leader, Darlene is engaged in promoting clinical and educational excellence throughout her facility to help improve patient outcomes. For nearly a decade, Darlene has served nationally and locally as an Association of periOperative Registered Nurses (AORN) leader. During her chapter presidency, Darlene led her chapter to be recognized nationally as a 'Chapter of Excellence'. She has also served as chair of AORN's Neuro, Ortho, & Trauma Specialty Assembly and on AORN's national membership and awards committees. Darlene was recognized as one of the Federation of Houston Professional Women's 'Woman of Excellence' in 2014. Darlene takes pride in giving back to her community by presenting her profession at Career Day events for Fort Bend and Houston School Districts' schools. Her passion, other than providing direct patient care, is sharing her knowledge. She is a certified CPR instructor, monthly newsletter editor-in-chief, AORN Journal author, and AORN National Convention poster and podium presenter. She is committed to lifelong learning and dedicated to providing safe compassionate evidence based care to all patients.

Experience

Memorial Hermann Health System Registered Nurse IV December 1993 - Present (26 years 6 months) Houston, Texas Area

Recognized as 'Expert' through the Memorial Hermann Hospital Professional Nurse Advancement Program. Perform circulating nurse responsibilities including patient assessment, operating room preparation, develop and coordinate specialized nursing care plans for critically injured patients using evidence based practices to improve the patient's outcome. Surgical Services monthly newsletter editor-in-chief. Peer Review Committee member. Chair of Magnet Council Professional Nurse Advancement Program and editor-in-chief of quarterly newsletter. Chair of the OR Nurse Quality Committee.

AORN

Board Of Directors April 2018 - Present (2 years 2 months) Denver

Manage the affairs of the Association. Provide strategic leadership. Help set the direction and visioin of the association ensuring the mission and the needs of the membership are at the forefront.

Education

The University of Texas Health Science Center at Houston Bachelors of Science, Registered Nursing/Registered Nurse · (1989 - 1992)

University of North Carolina at Charlotte
Bachelor of Arts (B.A.), Business Administration and Management,
General · (1979 - 1983)